synaptics.com 2019-05-28

# Privacy Policy | Synaptics

This Privacy Policy for Synaptics Web Sites describes information Synaptics collect, use, share, and store, including personal information (i.e., information that personally identifies you, such as your name, email address or billing information, or other data that can be reasonably used to infer this information).

This document focuses on information related to the operation of the public websites available at Synaptics.com and Synaptics.com sub- domains (each, a "Site"). We provide additional details about how we collect and use information in connection with Synaptics products and services in our Privacy Statement for Synaptics Products and Services.

COLLECTION AND USE: Synaptics collects information about you through our Sites in several ways. This information is used to provide users with Synaptics products and services, to allow us to understand how visitors navigate our Site, and to provide advertising that is relevant to your interests.

Mailing List Information: You may choose to submit your email address via a submission form located on our Site. Your email address may be used to send you news about Synaptics-related services, products or promotions. We may use one or more service providers to administer these messages, but we do not share your email address with spammers or any other third parties without your permission.

Online Tracking and Your Choices:

Website Use Information: Like many websites, we and our third-party partners analyze log file information and other data collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technology, to collect information about your browsing behavior when you visit our Site, including for example, your browser type, domains, page views, IP address, referring/exit pages, information about how you interact with our Site’s webpages and with third-party links, traffic and usage trends on the service, etc. We use session cookies to keep you logged in while you use features of our Site; these disappear after you close your browser. We also use persistent cookies, which stay in your browser and allow us to recognize you when you return to the Site. We use this to remember your information so you will not have to re-enter it, to better understand how you use our website and products and services, to diagnose and fix technology problems, and otherwise enhance our Site, products, and services. In some of our email messages, we use a "click-through URL" linked to content on the Site. We track this click-through data to help us measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. We also use third-party analytics tools (including Google Analytics) to assist us with analyzing and improving our service. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies, but you may be able to change the settings of your browser to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you set your browser to reject cookies, parts of our Site may not work for you. Please note, depending on your type of device or browser, it may not be possible to delete or disable all tracking mechanisms on your device.

  * Your selection of the "Do Not Track" option provided by your browser may not have any effect on our collection of cookie information for analytic and internal purposes. The only way to completely "opt out" of the collection of any information through cookies or other tracking technology is to actively manage the settings on your browser or mobile device to delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. (To learn more about cookies, clear gifs/web beacons and related technologies, you may wish to visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/)).

  * We may permit third-party advertising partners to use cookies and other technology to collect information about your browsing activities over time and across different websites when you use our Site. For example, the use of advertising services provided by third-party ad partners, such as Google Display Network and AdRoll, to market our services to you on other websites and online services. Through a process called "retargeting," each service places a cookie on your browser when you visit our Site so that they can identify you and serve you ads on other sites around the web based on your browsing activity. To avoid use of this information for advertising by these third-party ad partners, you can change your browser settings to reject cookies or to notify you when cookies are set and you could select the Do Not Track option on your browser, though we have no control over and cannot confirm whether these third party ad parties honor the Do Not Track browser signal. Additionally, many advertising companies are members of the NAI or DAA and/or provide opt-outs on those industry pages at [networkadvertising.org/choices](http://networkadve%20rtising.org/choices) or [aboutads.info/choices](http://aboutads.info/choices).

Third-Party Sites and Features: Our Site may contain links to other websites operated by third parties and may include social media features such as Facebook and Twitter buttons (such as "Like," "Tweet" or "Pin"). These third- party sites may collect information about you if you click on a link and the social media sites may automatically record information about your browsing behavior every time you visit a site that has a social media button. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the feature, not by our privacy policy. We do not control what information these third parties collect. Please review your privacy settings on your social media sites and think carefully before clicking on links which may take you to a third-party website.

Minors: Our Site does not knowingly collect or store any personal information about children under the age of 13.

DATA SHARING: Under no circumstance do we share personal information for any commercial or marketing purpose unrelated to the delivery of Synaptics Products and services without asking you first. We do not rent or sell our customer lists.

The following are the limited situations where we may share personal information:

  * For external processing: We have vendors, service providers, and technicians who help with some of our processing and storage, including helping to answer your questions. They may also assist with monitoring our servers for technical problems. These technicians (as well as Synaptics employees) can access certain information about you or your account in line with this work but these technicians are not allowed to use this data for non-Synaptics purposes. We also have strict policies and technical barriers in place to prevent unauthorized employee access to video data.

  * As part of business transitions: Upon the sale or transfer of the company and/or all or part of its assets, your personal information may be among the items sold or transferred. We will request a purchaser to treat our data under the privacy statement in place at the time of its collection.

  * For legal reasons: We may provide information to a third party if we believe in good faith that we are required to do so for legal reasons. For example, to respond to legal process, or comply with state and federal laws (or the applicable laws of foreign countries other than the United States).

Your personal information may be collected, processed and stored by Synaptics or its service providers in the United States and other countries where our servers reside. As a result, your personal information may be subject to legal requirements, including lawful requirements to disclose personal information to government authorities, in those jurisdictions.

SECURITY: Synaptics is committed to ensuring the security of your personal information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of personal information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure it.

GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION PRIVACY NOTICE

The purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation ("EU GDPR") is to ensure lawful, fair and transparent collection of all personal data of individuals, regardless of citizenry, in the European Union ("EU Data Subjects") by allowing them to maintain control of their personal data kept and processed by organizations, which includes Synaptics.

Synaptics is committed to safeguarding the privacy of personal data.  This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information collected by us through the Synaptics Web Sites.  When EU Data Subjects submit personal data to us, or use the Synaptics Web Sites and other services, EU Data Subjects consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of that information as described in this Privacy Notice.

This Privacy Notice should be read in conjunction with the Privacy Policy above.  In this Privacy Notice, we set out further information on the rights of EU Data Subjects under the EU GDPR.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, please contact our Data Protection Officer at DPO@synaptics.com.

Retention Timelines

The information that EU Data Subjects provide to us is stored on servers that are operated and maintained by us and third parties under contract with us.  We will only retain data for such period of time as may be reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes set out in the Privacy Policy above and, if relevant, to deal with any claim or dispute that might arise in connection with any services provided on the Synaptics Web Sites.

Transfers Abroad

In connection with the services provided on the Synaptics Web Sites, we may transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, including to a jurisdiction which is not recognized by the European Commission as providing for an equivalent level of protection for personal data as is provided for in the European Union.  If and to the extent that we do so, we will ensure that appropriate measures are in place to comply with our obligations under applicable law governing such transfers.  These may include entering into a contract governing the transfer that contains the ‘standard contractual clauses’ approved for this purpose by the European Commission or, in respect of transfers from the EU to the United States of America, ensuring that the transfer is covered by the EU-US Privacy Shield framework. If you would like to receive further details of the measures that we have taken in this regard, please contact us at DPO@synaptics.com

Your Rights.

Under the EU GDPR, EU Data Subjects have the following rights, which apply in certain circumstances and subject to certain restrictions, in relation to personal data:

  * the right to access your personal data;
  * the right to request the rectification and/or erasure of your personal data;
  * the right to restrict the use of your personal data;
  * the right to object to the processing of your personal data;
  * where our processing of personal data is based on you having provided your consent or the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, you have the right to receive your personal data, which you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format or to require us to transmit that data to another controller; and
  * where our processing of your personal data is based on you having provided consent, the right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us at DPO@synaptics.com.

Complaints

If you are not happy with the way we have used your information or addressed your rights, please contact us at DPO@synaptics.com.

In addition, you have the right to make a complaint to the supervisory authority of the EU member state in which you reside.

Effective Date: January 23, 2019.

Changes to Privacy Policy: Please note that this privacy policy may change from time to time. We will provide notice of any changes on the website or by contacting you.

If you have any questions please go to our Contact Us page. Last Updated: January 23, 2019
